https://irishmuseums.org/text-pages/privacy-policy

Join our Mailing List
The Irish Museums Association (IMA) takes the privacy of its members, subscribers and users very seriously and takes great care with the information we obtain. This Privacy Policy outlines how personal information is collected, used and protected as part of the terms and conditions of this website.It complies with the Data Protection Acts 1988 and 2003 (as amended or superseded, including from 25 May 2018 the General Data Protection Regulation) and other related legislation.This policy was approved by the board of directors of the IMA in 2018, replacing the privacy policy from 2006 and amended in 2012. We recommend that if you submit your personal data via this site, you check this page regularly to ensure you are happy with any subsequent updates.Who are the Data Controllers?The data controllers for the Irish Museums Association website are the Board of Directors of the Irish Museums Association.How to unsubscribe from our mailing listSubscription to Irish Museums Association's services is voluntary and you can choose to unsubscribe from any or all of Irish Museums Association's emails at any time, click on the relevant links on our website or in the emails we send you.Accessing and updating or erasing your personal informationA request for access to, update and/or erasure of, your personal information must be made in writing and addressed to Irish Museums Association, 11 Parnell Square East, D01 ND60. You should include a copy of your passport or driving licence. We will reply to you within 30 days.Third party sites and linksYou are able to access third party sites through links on our website. The Irish Museums Association is not responsible for and makes no representations concerning the condition of and content of, or products offered at the third party site or their commitment to Privacy Laws. Any link from the Irish Museums Association's website does not indicate, expressly or impliedly, that the Irish Museums Association endorses the site or the products or services offered there. If you access a third party site, it is at your own risk. It is recommended you check the terms and conditions and privacy policies of the sites you visit independently.The IMA uses third-party online services to collect, store and/or protect information, such as MailChimp, Google, iDrive, SurveyMonkey, and PayPal. Access to these sites is strictly confidential and restricted to the data processor and controllers. Debit and credit card information is not stored by the IMA.These servers are based in the US. The IMA makes every reasonable endeavour to ensure these sites, along with Facebook, Instagram and Twitter, have re committed to achieving compliance with the GDPR in 2018 and are updating their Data Processing Agreement and third-party vendor contracts to meet the GDPR's requirements. See their privacy policies here:The IMA complies with Google’s European Union User Consent Policy.The IMA has signed Mail Chimps’s Data Processing AgreementSurveyMonkey’s Privacy PolicyPayPal Privacy PolicyWhat personal information will we collect from you?We will only collect enough personal data from you to provide you with the service you have requested.If you sign up to our mailing service, we will ask for your email address as a requisite. The form will also collect your IP address, and timestamp associated with anyone who submits the form. You can provide your name, county, job title, and institution, for monitoring and reporting purposes (the information will be anonymised) and for tailored emails, but this is optional.We will also hold information you have supplied for other purposes - for example in connection with enquiries made via our contact form. By submitting information to us you are consenting to the management and use of your information as set out in this Privacy Policy.What do we do with your personal information?If you sign up to our subscriber list, we will use your personal information to send you emails with information on events, news, continued professional development, and career opportunities which may be of interest to you.If you supply your information for other purposes, for example if you send us an enquiry, we will only use your information for the purpose of answering your query. If we want to use your data for any purpose outside of the terms of this policy, we will ask you first.How long will we keep your information?The Irish Museums Association will keep your information for up to seven years after you actively discontinue your IMA membership. It will additionally monitor activity reports on our server and delete information on subscribers that show no activity for a sustained length of time (no less than two years, no more than seven years).Disclosure of personal informationYour personal information will be disclosed only to relevant representatives of the Irish Museums Association, companies or persons specifically contracted to manage data for the IMA in accordance with its instructions (see third-party site information), and if there is a legal obligation to do so. Only necessary information is disclosed. All reasonable steps are taken to ensure all information is accurate, complete and up to date. If your circumstances change, please let us know.Security of your personal informationWe are committed to ensuring your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We take appropriate steps to protect all of your personal information we hold from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. This protection applies in relation to information stored in both electronic and hard copy form. However you should be aware that internet transmissions can never be guaranteed to be always private or secure. You should assume that any message you send to the IMA website and servers may be read or intercepted by others unless there is an indication (such as the https padlock symbol) that the transmission has been encrypted.
Privacy PolicyCookies PolicyLegal InfoCopyright InfoJoin our Mailing List
